<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The geek behind the viewfinder]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-08T18:42:33+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alexander Almegaard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rejsekort - A sloppy attempt to digitalise the Danish public transportation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/rejsekort-the-desperate-attempt-to-digitalize-the-danish-public-transportation/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-20T11:35:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/rejsekort-the-desperate-attempt-to-digitalize-the-danish-public-transportation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“<em>Rejsekort (Official translation: TRAVEL CARD) is an electronic ticket system for public transport in Denmark. The system is a collaborative work between DSB, HUR, Ørestadsselskabet, and various regional bus companies, and work on it started on August 18, 2003.</em>”
(Wikipedia)</p>

<p>Okay. So they began the work in 2003? Then it must be up and running now, right? No? No. 10 years later and it is still not working properly. <strong>Not even close</strong>. In fact, the Danish State Railways just prolonged the use of the old ticket coupon for another year, due to problems with Rejsekort.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The ticket coupon system has been the cheapest and easiest way to travel around Copenhagen for many years. You buy a coupon valid for 10 trips with the number of zones you would like to travel. Everyone can buy it, everyone can use it. Before a trip you just validate the card at the station. It’s also easy to see how many trips you have left.</p>

<p>The new travel card is different in many ways. The first step is to order a card from [rejsekort.dk][ref1]. When you receive the card, you have to transfer money to the card via a special terminal or their own self service website. Now you are ready to use the card.
Whenever you use public transportation, you use the travel card to check in at a designated stand. When you have finished your journey you check out at another stand. Every time you change from metro to bus etc. you have to check in again. If four hours have passed and you haven’t checked out, you get fined 50 DKK. Thus the minimum card balance has to be 50 DKK to be able to check in.
I could keep going for two pages if I had to mention all the rules and regulations.</p>

<h2>So what’s wrong with it?</h2>

<p>Ordering a travel card. That should be easy. It isn’t.. There are over 6 different cards to choose from. Young, adult, child, senior, dog, bike, disabled etc. Furthermore you can choose a personal card, an anonymous card or a flex card. These different types of cards all have different rules and regulations. Shit.</p>

<p>Secondly, the travel card is NOT available for tourists. This means the tourists are restricted to buying standard tickets at twice the price of traveling with a ticket coupon. What were they thinking? It’s possible for tourists to get a city pass. But that’s only valid for a certain amount of hours.</p>

<p>If you are traveling with others it is possible to check in more people on one card. To do so you have to find a special stand. Only some of the stands is equipped with “the extra settings”. This is insane.</p>

<p>Because of the minimum card balance you can be stuck between changing transportation, not being able to check in because of a low card balance. When checking out, the stand shows the card balance, which you obviously then have to remember to be sure to be able to complete your next trip. Can I just check the card balance on their website then? Yeah, you can. But it’s not optimised for mobile use, at all. And, if you choose to transfer money to the card online, you have to wait 24 hours before you can use the card!</p>

<p>The travel card is also supposed to encourage some commuters to travel outside rush hours by adding a discount at certain hours of the day. That’s fine. But during the time I used the card I experienced odd pricing and several times I was charged more than I expected. The pricing is different than the known ticket coupon and certainly not transparent enough.</p>

<p>The worst thing is that the new travel card system isn’t connected to the the existing commute pass. Even though you already payed your monthly fee for traveling in specific zones, the travel card doesn’t know that, and you risk to pay for the same area twice.</p>

<p><strong>Have anyone thought this through before deciding to spend over 1 billion DKK on the project?</strong></p>

<p>For now, the use of the old ticket coupons is prolonged and we can only hope that someone will wake up and turn the project around. The travel card definitely has potential as we have seen in other countries, but there is still a lot to fix.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Boxee Box - pros, cons, and hacks]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/the-boxee-box-pros-cons-and-hacks/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-20T11:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/the-boxee-box-pros-cons-and-hacks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At one point, connecting a computer to the TV to watch local media files became too much of a bother. Since then, I have been using the <a href="http://www.dlink.com/us/en/home-solutions/boxee-box/at-a-glance"><em>Boxee Box</em></a> to stream content from my local NAS to the TV.</p>

<p>The Boxee is connected with an ethernet cable and to the TV via HDMI. When it is plugged in, the next thing to do is to add the local media sources. Then the Boxee scans the sources, sorts all media files according to movies and shows, and labels them with the right title, description, and cover image.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>The Boxee Box supports up to 1080p, digital audio output, Wi-Fi and ethernet, and streaming video and audio from an iOS device. Despite these great features, it has still got a lot of weak points.</p>

<h2>Pros</h2>

<ul>
<li>Supports <strong>a lot</strong> of different formats, including AVI, MKV and DivX.</li>
<li>Easy to install and setup.</li>
<li>Clean and good looking interface.</li>
<li>Ability to install new firmware.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Cons</h2>

<ul>
<li>Unstable performance.</li>
<li>Slow start-up.</li>
<li>Does not support 5GHz Wi-Fi.</li>
<li>Discontinued by D-Link which means no bug fixes.</li>
</ul>


<p>Not being able to connect the Boxee to a 5GHz network resulted in having to use the ethernet port. The 2.4GHz band is simply too crowded in this area to handle 1080p video streaming. The ethernet solution takes care of the buffering problem. In addition to this, the Boxee is extremely unstable and the firmware really needs an update.</p>

<h2>Boxee+Hacks</h2>

<p><em>Boxee+Hacks</em> is a new open-source software for the Boxee Box. It comes with a bunch of new UI features and bug fixes. To install Boxee+Hacks on a Boxee follow <a href="http://boxeeplus.com/">this</a> guide.</p>

<blockquote><p>Note: Before you start, make sure you know what you are doing. This software is not affiliated with Boxee and may void your warranty.</p></blockquote>

<p>After <em>updating</em> the firmware you are presented with an extra settings panel, a new start up screen and a new screensaver. Updates are available every 2-3 months. I think the update has made the Boxee more stable, but it is still not perfect. The new ways of customising the home screen, subtitles, etc., are nice and I can’t see any way the Boxee+Hacks software makes the Boxee Box worse.</p>

<p>I think that the Boxee Box has great potential to be one of the best <em>omnivorous</em> set top boxes on the market — especially when it comes to streaming your own video content from local storage. It seriously needs a power boost, software or/and hardware wise, to bring down the loading time and how the firmware runs in general. If D-Link decided to launch a new upgraded Boxee Box, I would definitely consider to get it. As the current Boxee Box runs now it a bit too expensive compared to other boxes on the market.</p>

<h2>Alternatives</h2>

<p>There are a bunch of alternatives including <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/browse/home/shop_ipod/ipod_accessories/apple_tv">Apple TV</a>, <a href="http://www.google.com/tv/">Google TV</a>, <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/">Raspberry Pi</a>, <a href="http://www.roku.com/">Roku</a>, <a href="http://www.wdc.com/en/products/products.aspx?id=330">WD TV Live</a>.<br/>
Lifehacker has a good overview <a href="http://lifehacker.com/5946193/how-to-find-the-best-tv-set-top-box-and-ditch-cable-once-and-for-all">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On location photography with the ipad mini]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/on-location-photography-with-the-ipad-mini/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-17T22:16:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/on-location-photography-with-the-ipad-mini</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a month ago I was invited to photograph the annual event by <a href="http://dansic.org">DANSIC</a> (Danish Social Innovation Club). The event is a full day conference for 300 students, speakers, and organisers taking place in Copenhagen.
During the past couple of years I have photographed a lot of similar events and I really enjoy doing so. The combination of photography and getting to experience the fantastic entrepreneurship vibe is just amazing.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Gear and workflow</h2>

<p>Before leaving for a photo job I always review my gear. I make sure it is charged, cleaned and working properly. Since a lot of these events are full day events I always pack according to the conditions, to prevent myself from having to carry a bag that is unnecessarily heavy. I also used to bring my Macbook Air to be able to review, process, and upload some of the shots, on site. Despite the Air being lightweight and very compact, in most cases, it just isn’t small enough to carry around all day when also carrying a bag of photo gear.</p>

<p>This is where the iPad Mini joins the game. It fits in my <a href="http://store.lowepro.com/stealth-reporter-d300-aw">Lowepro Stealth Reporter</a> like a charm and weighs nothing. With the <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/MD821ZM/A/lightning-to-usb-camera-adapter?fnode=3a">Lightning to USB Camera Adaptor</a> it is possible to connect the USB cable from the camera directly to the iPad Mini. When the camera is turned on and connected to the iPad, the iPad automatically loads all the images from the camera as thumbnails. With 3-400 images on the camera it takes about 20 seconds to load all the thumbnails. To review or process an image select it and choose <strong>import</strong>. The import process takes about 2 seconds for a 15 MB RAW image.  When the import is done you can choose to <strong>delete</strong> the images or <strong>keep</strong> them on the camera. The imported images are placed in your <strong>photos</strong> app. From there you can access them from other apps and do with them what you want.</p>

<p>I use Aperture for the <em>serious</em> part of processing images, on the Air. On the iPad, <a href="http://www.snapseed.com/">Snapseed</a> is my favourite app. During DANSIC I uploaded several images to Twitter and mailed images to some of the sponsors. Whenever I had to do so, I just pulled out the iPad Mini, connected the camera, imported the images, made a few adjustments in Snapseed, and they were ready to upload or pass on. Easy, quick, and doable while standing in a crowd without a place to put the gear.</p>

<p>After the event I processed everything in Aperture and delivered the images to the Social Media Department of DANSIC. The images are available at <a href="http://www.facebook.com/danishsocialinnovationclub">DANSICs Facebook Page</a> and on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/almegaard/sets/72157633267126419/">Flickr</a>. More about my Aperture workflow some other time.</p>

<h2>Summary..</h2>

<p>..of my experience with the iPad Mini as an <em>on location photography partner</em>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Easier and quicker to use than the Air.</li>
<li>Fits in most photo bags.</li>
<li>Lacks the possibility to preview in full size.</li>
<li>Reduced options when processing (Snapseed).</li>
<li>Supports RAW format.</li>
<li>Limited to exporting in JPG (Snapseed).</li>
</ul>


<p>An alternative to the adaptor could be an <a href="http://www.eye.fi/">Eye-Fi</a> card which enables the camera to transfer images to an iPad or computer using a built-in Wi-Fi. But since Eye-Fi only produces SD cards and my DSLR is CF only, this was not an option for me. Eye-Fi cards begin at $39.99 and the Lightning to USB Camera Adaptor is $29.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ready for takeoff]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/ready-for-takeoff/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-16T10:46:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/ready-for-takeoff</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New blog - let’s get going!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
