<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ipad | The geek behind the viewfinder]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/blog/categories/ipad/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-07-08T18:53:59+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Alexander Almegaard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On location photography with the ipad mini]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.almegaard.com/on-location-photography-with-the-ipad-mini/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-17T22:16:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.almegaard.com/on-location-photography-with-the-ipad-mini</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a month ago I was invited to photograph the annual event by <a href="http://dansic.org">DANSIC</a> (Danish Social Innovation Club). The event is a full day conference for 300 students, speakers, and organisers taking place in Copenhagen.
During the past couple of years I have photographed a lot of similar events and I really enjoy doing so. The combination of photography and getting to experience the fantastic entrepreneurship vibe is just amazing.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Gear and workflow</h2>

<p>Before leaving for a photo job I always review my gear. I make sure it is charged, cleaned and working properly. Since a lot of these events are full day events I always pack according to the conditions, to prevent myself from having to carry a bag that is unnecessarily heavy. I also used to bring my Macbook Air to be able to review, process, and upload some of the shots, on site. Despite the Air being lightweight and very compact, in most cases, it just isn’t small enough to carry around all day when also carrying a bag of photo gear.</p>

<p>This is where the iPad Mini joins the game. It fits in my <a href="http://store.lowepro.com/stealth-reporter-d300-aw">Lowepro Stealth Reporter</a> like a charm and weighs nothing. With the <a href="http://store.apple.com/us/product/MD821ZM/A/lightning-to-usb-camera-adapter?fnode=3a">Lightning to USB Camera Adaptor</a> it is possible to connect the USB cable from the camera directly to the iPad Mini. When the camera is turned on and connected to the iPad, the iPad automatically loads all the images from the camera as thumbnails. With 3-400 images on the camera it takes about 20 seconds to load all the thumbnails. To review or process an image select it and choose <strong>import</strong>. The import process takes about 2 seconds for a 15 MB RAW image.  When the import is done you can choose to <strong>delete</strong> the images or <strong>keep</strong> them on the camera. The imported images are placed in your <strong>photos</strong> app. From there you can access them from other apps and do with them what you want.</p>

<p>I use Aperture for the <em>serious</em> part of processing images, on the Air. On the iPad, <a href="http://www.snapseed.com/">Snapseed</a> is my favourite app. During DANSIC I uploaded several images to Twitter and mailed images to some of the sponsors. Whenever I had to do so, I just pulled out the iPad Mini, connected the camera, imported the images, made a few adjustments in Snapseed, and they were ready to upload or pass on. Easy, quick, and doable while standing in a crowd without a place to put the gear.</p>

<p>After the event I processed everything in Aperture and delivered the images to the Social Media Department of DANSIC. The images are available at <a href="http://www.facebook.com/danishsocialinnovationclub">DANSICs Facebook Page</a> and on <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/almegaard/sets/72157633267126419/">Flickr</a>. More about my Aperture workflow some other time.</p>

<h2>Summary..</h2>

<p>..of my experience with the iPad Mini as an <em>on location photography partner</em>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Easier and quicker to use than the Air.</li>
<li>Fits in most photo bags.</li>
<li>Lacks the possibility to preview in full size.</li>
<li>Reduced options when processing (Snapseed).</li>
<li>Supports RAW format.</li>
<li>Limited to exporting in JPG (Snapseed).</li>
</ul>


<p>An alternative to the adaptor could be an <a href="http://www.eye.fi/">Eye-Fi</a> card which enables the camera to transfer images to an iPad or computer using a built-in Wi-Fi. But since Eye-Fi only produces SD cards and my DSLR is CF only, this was not an option for me. Eye-Fi cards begin at $39.99 and the Lightning to USB Camera Adaptor is $29.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
